Guide to the World War I Pamphlet Collection 1901-1944 (bulk 1914-1919)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Europe - Peace Concerns / Discussions (in English), 1914-1916 and undated; Thomas, Benton H. An open letter respectfully submitted to our president to the allies and to the world. n.d. (2 copies); Schevill, Ferdinand. Germany and the Peace of Europe. 1914.; Bell, Edward Price. A Free Europe: Being an Interview with the Rt. Hon. Sir Edward Grey, Bart., K.G. British Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs. T. Fisher Unwin, Ltd.: London, 1916. (2 copies) (Box-folder 6/14)
- Europe - Peace Concerns / Discussions (in English), 1917; McCormick, Harold Fowler. Via Pacis; How Terms of Peace Can Be Automatically Prepared While the War Is Still Going On. Chicago: A.C. McClurg, 1917.; Germany. The German Note and the Reply of the Allies. London: T.F. Unwin, Ltd, 1917. (2 copies) (Box-folder 6/15)
- Europe - Peace Concerns / Discussions (in English), 1918-1919; The North American. Pitfalls of Peace: Germany's Offers and President Wilson's Replies. The North American: Philadelphia, 1918.; Nippold, Otfried, and Alexander Gray. The Awakening of the German People. New York: George H. Doran Co, 1918.; Kahn, Otto Hermann. Frenzied Liberty: The Myth of "a Rich Man's War". New York?: s.n, 1918.; Becker, Carl Lotus. America's War Aims and Peace Program. 1918. (missing front cover); Memorial to the members of the Peace congress in Paris, 1919; on address on behalf of the Roumanian emigrants and refugees of Austria-Hungary (Transylvania, Bucovine, Maramuresh, Crishana and Banat), resident in the United States and Canada. In the cause of the unity of their provinces with the Roumanian state. Paris, 1919. (Box-folder 7/1)
- Europe - Peace Concerns / Discussions (in French), 1917; Garton Foundation (Paris). Mémorandum sur les conditions de paix. Paris: the Garton foundation, 1917. (pamphlet is in French, but accomanying it is a three-page memorandum in English detailing the contents of the pamphlet) (Box-folder 7/2)
- Europe - Peace Concerns / Discussions (in various languages), 1930 and undated; International Federation of Trade Unions. Nie wieder krieg! = No more war! = Plus jamais de guerre! = Nunca jamas guerra! = Nooit meer oorlag! = Aldrig mere kri! Amsterdam: International Federation of Trade Unions, 1930.; Message listed in 27 different languages about international free trade being essential to peace. n.d. (Box-folder 7/3)
- Europe - Reconstruction (in English), 1914-1919 and undated; Reichstadt-Napoleon, Prince. A Few War Preventives. New York, n.d.; Perry, Stuart H. After the War. The North American Review Publishing Co.: New York, 1914.; Cain, Professor William. Commencement Exercises of The Citadel, The Military College of South Carolina: Address by Professor William Cain of the University of North Carolina. Charleston: The Daggett Printing Co., 1918.; Hobson, J. A. The World Safe for Democracy. New York: National Civil Liberties Bureau, 1918. (2 copies; extremely fragile); McCleary, J. N. Our Bit in Reconstruction: For Thinking Men. Washington, 1919. (Box-folder 7/4)
- Europe - Reconstruction (in English), 1920-1943; Griffiths, Austin E. The Salvation or Wreck of Europe: America's Share Therein. [Seattle, Wash.]: Seattle Union Record, 1923.; Brigham, Albert Perry, and Charles T. McFarlane. Results of the World War. New York: American Book Co, 1920.; Introduction to the work of the Society of Friends in European Agricultural Reconstruction (1914-1924), with regard to possible contributions in the future. London: Joint Research Department, 1943. (Box-folder 7/5)
- Europe - Reconstruction (in French), 1918; Brijancaninov, A N. Les neutres, le ravitaillement et la question sociale: Une propositon pratique. Copenhagen, 1918. (Box-folder 7/6)
- Europe - Reparations: Owed by the Central Powers (in English), 1919-1922 and undated; Phillips, W. B. and Associates. The Reparations Problem. London, n.d.; Economical & Financial Delegation of the Kingdom of the Serbians, Coatians and Slovenes. To the Commission for Reparation of Damages at the Peace Conference. Paris: Impr. "Graphique", 1919.; What reparations has Germany already made? 1922. (2 copies); Moldenke, Dr. Richard. The Inside History of Germany's Appeal to President Harding to mediate in the Reparations Question. 1922. (Written in 1922 concerning events occurring in March to May 1921 in the time of the administration of President Harding) (Box-folder 7/7)
- Europe - Reparations: Owed by the Central Powers (in English), 1926-1931; Wells, Gabriel. If I Were France. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, Page, 1926.; Luther, Hans. Address Delivered at the Press Reception of the Leipzig Fair March 1, 1931. Berlin: Druckerei der Reichsbank, 1931.; Luther, Hans. Address by Dr. Hans Luther delivered at the International Rotary meeting held in Luxembourg May 2nd 1931. Berlin: Druckerei der Reichsbank, 1931. (2 copies); Cadoux, Gaston. Our war losses: their reparations and war debts. Nancy: Berger-Levrault's Printing Office, 1926. (Box-folder 7/8)
- Europe - Treaty of Versailles / Armistice (in English), 1915-1918 and undated; Unconditional Surrender. Baltimore: Manufacturers Record, n.d. (business card); Lambert, Henri. The False Peace: Protectionism Means Endless Conflict. Boston: The International Free Trade League, n.d.; What Shall Be America's Answer to German Peace Pleas? Baltimore: Manufacturers Record Publishing Co., n.d. (extremely fragile); Wisconsin Peace Society. Mediation Without Armistice The Wisconsin Plan. Madison. Wisconsin: The Wisconsin Peace Society, 1915.; Union of Democratic Control. Suggestions for Terms of a Peace Settlement. London: Union of Democratic Control, 1917.; Wilson, Woodrow. Self-Determination and the Rights of Small Nations. Dublin: Candle Press, 1918. (Box-folder 7/9)
- Europe - Treaty of Versailles/Armistice (in English), 1919-1923 and undated; American Peace Society. Thinking It Through in Paris: Three Documents. Washington, D.C.: American Peace Society, 1919.; Seaman, Louis Livingston. Shall the Treaty of Peace Be One of Justice or One of Infamy? Washington: U.S. G.P.O., 1919.; American Peace Society. Suggestive Memoranda for the Honorable Commissioners to Negotiate Peace, Paris. Washington D.C.: The American Peace Society, 1919.; Brentano, Lujo. What Germany has paid under the Treaty of Versailles. Berlin: Walter de Gruyter, 1923. (fragile); Schwertfeger, Colonel Bernhard. The Mistake of Versailles: Germany's acquittal proved by Belgian documents 1871-1914. 1921.; Comparative Table of the Articles of the Garman, Austrian, Hungarian, Bulgarian, and Turkish Treaties. n.d. (fragile) (Box-folder 7/10)
- Europe - Treaty of Versailles / Armistice (in German), 1923-1929; Brentano, Lujo. Was Deutschland gezahlt hat; die bisherigen deutschen Leistungen auf Grund des Vertrages von Versailles. Berlin: W. de Gruyter, 1923.; Wegerer, Alfred von. Die Widerlegung der Versailler Kriegsschuldthese. I. Entstehung und Umfang der Versailler Kriegsschuldthese. II. Widerlegung des "Rapport". Berlin: [Preussische Druckerei- und Verlags-Aktiengesellschaft], 1928.; Kaehler, Siegfried A. Vom geschichtlichen Erlebnisgehalt der Versailler Schuldthese: akademische Vorlesung. Breslau: Trewendt & Granier, 1929. (Box-folder 7/11)
- Europe - War Agencies (in English), 1941; National Archives (U.S.). List of Federal World War Agencies, 1914-20. Washington: National Archives, 1941. (Box-folder 7/12)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Entente's Viewpoint (in English), 1914-1917 and undated; Wells, Frank M. War with Germany and Why We Won, by an ex-army chaplain. n.d.; Bihn, Ernest F. War for Opinion, or an analysis of the cause and effect of the war. Chicago: Iconoclast Publishing, Co., n.d.; Raymond, Jerome Hall. The War - What for? The Underlying Causes of the War Madness in Europe. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1914. (syllabus series of the University Extension Division); Funk, Henry Daniel. Aspects of European Diplomacy Since 1878. Saint Paul: Franklin Press, 1915.; Chase, Wayland Johnson. The Great War. A Study Outline of the Causes, the Immediate Background, and the Beginnings of the Great War. Madison: [University of Wisconsin], 1917.; Henshaw, F. W. The Cause and Meaning of This War. The Argonaut Press, 1917.; Girard. Mighty Fist of British Empire as seen in this War: for the Pennsylvania Council of National Defense and Committee of Public Safety. n.d. (Box-folder 7/13)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Entente's Viewpoint (in English), 1918-1919; Lyle Jr., Eugene P. The War of 1938. New York: American Defense Society, Inc., 1918.; Kahn, Otto Hermann. When the Tide Turned: The American Attack at Chateau Thierry and Belleau Wood in the First Week of June, 1918. Boston, Mass.?: s.n, 1918.; Klipstein, E. C. The Struggle of Civilization against Kultur. New Jersey: 1918. (pro-Aryan text); Harding, Samuel Bannister. The Study of the Great War: A Topical Outline with Copious Quotations and Reading References. Philadelphia, Pa: McKinley Pub. Co, 1918.; Chronological Record of the Great World War and Pictures of the Famous Cathedral at Rheims France so often Bombarded by the Germans during the War. Detroit: George W. Blank, 1919.; German Colonial Methods; A collection of English, French and American criticisms. Bern: R. Dech & Co., 1919.; Bunau-Varilla, Lt. Colonel. The Occult Power of Germany: Extract of an Address of Lt. Colonel Bunau-Varilla to the Ohio Society of New York, at the "Victory Banquet" of January 11th 1919. 1919. (Box-folder 7/14)
- Europe - War Guilt/Blame: Entente's Viewpoint (in English), 1923-1928; Bruce, Stewart E. An Open Letter to the President of the United States on the Duty and Responsibility of America in the World Crisis. Pasadena, Calif.?: Stewart Bruce?, 1923.; Nover, Barnet. Why War Came: A Reconsideration in the Light of the Latest Available Evidence of the Diplomatic Negotiations Leading to the Outbreak of the World War in 1914. [Buffalo, N.Y.]: The Buffalo Evening News, 1925.; Staggers, John W. What Caused the Early, Unexpected and Sudden Termination of Hostilities in the World War? Washington D. C.: 1926.; Peabody, Frederick W. The Prime Ministers to the President. Ashburnham, Mass.: The American Association Favoring Reconsideration of the War Debt, 1928. (Box-folder 7/15)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Entente's Viewpoint (in English), 1932-1944; Ballin, Fred A. The Causes and Consequences of the World War, Iniquity and Retribution. Author?, 1932.; O'Shea, Francis Bernard. Retrospect. 1936. (personal narrative); Yanov, Emil. The Assassination of Arch-Duke Frans Ferdinand and Princess Jelisava at Sarajevo, June 28, 1914. Boston: The Meador Press, 1944. (Box-folder 8/1)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in Dutch), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/2)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in English), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/3)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in English), 1934-1935; Vollbehr, Otto H. F. Is Pacifism Possible?: A Reply. S.l: s.n.], 1934.; Neurath, Konstantin Freiherr von. Germany's Foreign Policy. New York: Forum Magazine, 1935. (Box-folder 8/4)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in French), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/5)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in German), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/6)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in Italian), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/7)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in Portuguese), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/8)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in Spanish), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/9)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Germany's Viewpoint (in Swedish), 1931; Fichte Association-Union for World Veracity. Notruf. Hamburg: Deutscher Fichtebund, 1931. [(extremely fragile) (series of leaflets, includes several interviews with Hitler)] (Box-folder 8/10)
- Europe - War Guilt / Blame: Pro-German Viewpoint (in English), 1915 and undated; Was Germany Solely Responsible for the War? Brookline, MA: The Association to Abolish War, n.d.; Chamberlain, Houston Stewart. Who Is to Blame for the War? New York, N.Y.: German-American Literary Defense Committee, 1915. (Box-folder 8/11)
- Finland - Foreign Politics (in English and French), 1915-1921; Hoving, Johannes Walter Wilhelm. Finland, the Buffer-State of Europe. New York: German-American Literary Defense Committee, 1915.; Hedengren, Torsten. Save Finland from Germany and Starvation. New York: The Finland Constitutional League of America, 1918.; la Société de Géographie de Finlande. Les frontières de Finlande.: Description succinte des limites de la republique. Fennia. 42, No.10. Helsingfors: Un Comité nommé par la Société de Géographie de Finlande, 1921. [(extremely fragile) (the map of Finland that accompanies this item is located in OS 45)] (Box-folder 8/12)
- Finland - Foreign Politics (in French and Finnish), 1921; Societe de Goegraphie de Finlande. Finlande, Suoml Finland. Helsinki: Maanmittaushallituksen kivipaino, 1921. (this map accompanies the publication "Les frontieres de Finlande," located in Box 8, folder 12) (Box OS 45)
- France - Atrocities / Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1915; France, and Georges Payelle. German Atrocities in France; A Translation of the Official Report of the French Commission. Londres: Impr. United newspapers, Ltd, 1915. [(extremely fragile) (2 copies)] (Box-folder 8/13)
- France - Atrocities/Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1915; Seignobos, Charles. 1815-1915, from the Congress of Vienna to the War of 1914. Studies and documents on the war. Studies and documents on the war. Paris: A. Colin, 1915. (2 copies); Bédier, Joseph, and Bernhard Harrison. German Atrocities from German Evidence. Studies and documents on the war. Paris: A. Colin, 1915. (2 copies); Durkheim, Émile. "Germany Above All"; German Mentality and War. Studies and documents on the war. Paris: A. Colin, 1915. (Box-folder 8/14)
- France - Atrocities / Deportations Alleged in English: Against Germany (in English), 1915; Andler, Charles. Pan-Germanism: Its Plans for German Expansion in the World. Studies and documents on the war. Paris: A. Colin, 1915.; Weiss, André, and Walter Thomas. The Violation by Germany of the Neutrality of Belgium and Luxemburg. Studies and documents on the war. Paris: A. Colin, 1915.; Durkheim, Émile, and Ernest Denis. Who Wanted War? The Origin of the War According to Diplomatic Documents. Studies and documents on the war. Paris: A. Colin, 1915. (Box-folder 8/15)
- France - Atrocities / Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1917; Madelin, Louis, and Lilly M. Grove. The Victory of the Marne; The Enemy's Onslaught--Order to Stand Firm--the Battle--Immediate Results--Historic Consequences. Studies and documents on the war. Paris: A. Colin, 1917.; Frightfulness in Retreat. Proceedings of the French Senate, March 31st, 1917. Official report of the French commission appointed to investigate acts committed by the enemy in violation of the law of nations. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917. (2 copies) (Box-folder 8/16)
- France - Atrocities/Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1917; France. The Deportation of Women and Girls from Lille. New York, N.Y.: George H. Doran Co, 1917. (Box-folder 8/17)
- France - Atrocities / Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1917; Toynbee, Arnold Joseph. The German Terror in France. London: Hodder & Stoughton, 1917. (Box-folder 9/1)
- France - Atrocities/Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in French), undated; Bertrand, Georges. Au Pilori de l'Histoire: Les Ouvriers du Pan-Germanisme. Paris: n. d.; Le Sac de Dinant. n.d.; Le Lois de la Guerre ne Justifient pas les Atrocites Allemands. n. d.; Crinon, J. La Tyrannie des Kommandanturs. n.d. (2 copies; extremely fragile); L'Allemagne a Voulu la Guerre. n.d. (trifold pamphlet, each page titled separately) (2 partial copies) (Box-folder 9/2)
- France - Atrocities / Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in French), 1915; France, and Georges Payelle. Le livre rouge: les atrocités allemandes; rapport officiel et in-extenso présenté à M. le président du conseil le 7 janvier 1915. Paris: Bibliothèque des ouvrages documentaires, 1915.; Clunet, Edouard. La guerre allemande par la combustion, l'asphyxie et l'empoisonnement de l'adversaire. 1915. (Box-folder 9/3)
- France - Atrocities/Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in French), 1917-1919; Contribution a la Guerre Allemande par la destruction et le pillage systematiques des pays occupes... Paris: Marchal et Godde, 1917.; Ledebour, Georg. Tumultes au Reichstag: l'Allemagne impériale devant ses juges: discours prononcés au Reichstag par les députés Ledebour, Herzfeld, Cohn et Haase du Parti Socialiste Indépendant. Genève: Atar, 1918. (2 copies); Nouvelles atrocités Austro-Allemandes. Commises envers les officiers et soldats Yougoslaves. Au cours de l'année 1919. Documents officiels. Paris: Imp. "graphique", 1919.; Celarié, Henriette. Les jeunes filles déportées par les allemands. [Paris]: Impr. Bloud et Gay, 1919. (Box-folder 9/4)
- France - Atrocities/Deportations Alleged: Against Germany (in French), 1918; Les crimes des barbares: les atrocités sur Terre, sur Mer et dans les Airs. Montrouge: La Semeuse, 1918. (2 copies; extremely fragile) (Box OS 44)
- France - Domestic Politics (in French), 1918; Ligue des droits de l'homme (Paris, France). Affaire Malvy; étude juridique. Paris: [Impr. du Palais, 1918.; Ligue des droits de l'homme (Paris, France). L'Offensive du 16 Avril: La Legende et la Verite. Paris: [Impr. du Palais, 1918.; Lavisse, Ernest. France-humanité: lettres à une normalienne [sur l'enseignement civique en France et Allemagne]. Paris: Imprimerie I. Rirachovski, 1918.; La carte individuelle d'alimentation et les tickets de consommation: instruction générale, loi, décret, arrêtés. Paris: Service central des cartes, 1918. (booklet explaining the ration card system) (Box-folder 9/5)
- France - Economics and Finance: Industry (in English and French), 1917 and undated; Stopford, Edward A. Notes on Agricultural Co-Operation in France. Dublin: Irish Agricultural Organisation Society, n. d.; Beslay, A. Au travail dans l'après-guerre: le relèvement industriel en France, la crise des usines de munitions, charbonnages et métallurgie, la pénurie de main-d'oeuvre, la petite industrie, le blocus industriel. Genève: Georg, 1917. (Box-folder 9/6)
- France - Foreign Political Studies (in French), 1927; Renouvin, M. Cours de M. Renouvin: L'Independance de la Belgique. Paris: Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales et Centre européen de la Dotation Carnegie, 1927.; Tibal, M. Cours de M. Tibal: Les Tcheques. Paris: Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales et Centre européen de la Dotation Carnegie, 1927.; Tibal. Roumanie: Cours de M. Tibal Mercredi, 19 Janvier 1927. Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales, 1927.; Tibal, M. Cours de M. Tibal: Le Mouvement Yougoslave tel qu'il s'est presente immediatement avant la Guerre. Paris: Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales et Centre européen de la Dotation Carnegie, 1927.; Tibal, André. Cours de M. Tibal: Le mouvement national des minorites de l'Autriche-Hongrie pendant la guerre 1914-1918. Paris: Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales et Centre européen de la Dotation Carnegie, 1927. (Box-folder 9/7)
- France - Foreign Politics (in French), 1914; La Revue de Bourgogne. Dijon: Darantiere, 1914. (Box-folder 9/8)
- France - Foreign Politics (in French), 1915-1917; Beyens, Eugène-Napoléon. La Semaine Tragique. Bruxelles et Paris: G. van Oest et Cie, 1915.; Bureaux de L'Action Nationale. La Situation Alimentaire dans les Pays Ennemis. Paris, 1917. (Box-folder 9/9)
- France - Foreign Politics (in French), circa 1930s; Martin, William H. H. Les evenements de Juillet 1914. France, 1930s. (Box-folder 9/10)
- France - Foreign Politics: Alsace-Lorraine Disputes (in English), 1917-1919; Warren, Whitney. The Question of Alsace and Lorraine: Lecture Given at Aeolian Hall, New York, March 14, 1917. London: Ligue Patriotique des Alsaciens-Lorrains, 1917.; Schack, Albert P. Alsace-Lorraine: Its History, Values, etc., and a Plan for its just Settlement between France and Germany. New York: 1918.; The Executive Committee of the Free State, Elsass-Lothringen. The Protest of Young Alsace. 1919.; Lauzanne, Stéphane. Why France Wants Alsace-Lorraine. United States?: s.n, 1919. (2 copies) (Box-folder 9/11)
- France - Foreign Politics: Alsace-Lorraine Disputes (in French), 1917; Visite de S.E.M. Sharp, ambassadeur des Etats-Unis en France aux citeś eṕrouveés de Lorraine. Nancy: Rigot], 1917.; Pfister, Christian & l'Union amicale d'Alsace-Lorraine. Annales d'Alsace: Notre Alsace. Paris: Bibliotheque d'Alsace-Lorraine, 1917.; l'Union amicale d'Alsace-Lorraine. Annales d'Alsace: l'Alsace et la Lorraine pendant la guerre de 1870. Paris: Bibliotheque d'Alsace-Lorraine, 1917.; l'Union amicale d'Alsace-Lorraine. Annales d'Alsace: l'Alsace-Lorraine de Demain. Paris: Bibliotheque d'Alsace-Lorraine, 1917.; l'Union amicale d'Alsace-Lorraine. Annales d'Alsace: Pour l'Alsace-Lorraine. Paris: Bibliotheque d'Alsace-Lorraine, 1917.; l'Union amicale d'Alsace-Lorraine. Annales d'Alsace: l'Alsace-Lorraine pendant la grande Guerre. Paris: Bibliotheque d'Alsace-Lorraine, 1917. (Box-folder 9/12)
- France - Foreign Politics: Alsace-Lorraine Disputes (in French), 1918-1934 and undated; Motte, Eugène, and André Lebon. Documents sur la préparation de l'après-guerre. L'Alsace-Lorraine et les régions envahies. Discours prononcés... par MM. André Lebon, Eugène Motte et l'abbé Wetterlé. Paris: Belin frères, 1919.; Une Oeuvre d'Assistance aux Enfants Lorrains en Peril. n.d.; Questions d'Alsace-Lorraine; Elsass Lothringische Zeitfragen. Imprimerie P. Granchamp, June 1918. (serial publication); Lestien, G. L'Action du Général Foch a la Bataille de la Marne. Paris: 1934. (Box-folder 9/13)
- France - Foreign Politics: Alsace-Lorraine Disputes (in German), 1918-1919; Elsaß-lothringen: Von einem elsässischen Feldgrauen. Kriegspreffeamt, 1918.; Das elsaß-lothringen Symbol: Von einem Ultelsäßer. Bern: Semminger vorm J. Heuberger, 1919. (Box-folder 9/14)
- France - Foreign Relations: Franco-American (in English), 1918; Paris Chamber of Commerce. The Assistance Given by the United States in the War. Facts about the War, a bulletin of information. Paris, 1918. (Box-folder 9/15)